good afternoon welcome to ask the JDK
下午好，欢迎问一下JDK
are
是
we are here to answer questions
我们在这里回答问题
hopefully you are here to ask questions
希望你在这里问问题
if not we can all leave this is one of
如果不是，我们都可以离开，这是其中之一
the shortest slide decks I've ever
我所见过的最短的滑板
created don't believe a word we say ask
创造了不相信我们说的一个字问
questions if you're shy or if you're out
询问您是害羞还是外出
there on the internet watching the
在互联网上观看
stream you can tweet questions at me and
您可以向我发送问题，
I will select and read a limited number
我将选择并阅读有限的数量
of them so who wants to go first I know
他们中的谁，谁想先走，我知道
by the way if you're in the room that's
顺便说一句，如果你在房间里
why we need the other microphone sorry
为什么我们需要另一个麦克风
if you're in the room please come up
如果你在房间里，请来
here to ask your question because if we
在这里问你的问题，因为如果我们
repeat it we will distort it and that
重复一遍，我们会扭曲它，那
way everybody can hear what you're
每个人都能听到你的声音的方式
saying I like distorting the questions
说我喜欢扭曲问题
what you can destroy it okay
你能摧毁它好吗
nope come up here please
不，请过来这里
so I would I was just attending meeting
所以我会参加会议
a session before this one about jigsaw
在此之前有关拼图的会议
and I was wondering if I'm doing
我想知道我是否在做
development at a client I'm building
我要建立的客户的开发
some libraries and I've got you've got
一些图书馆，我有你
your XML files public-private that kind
您的XML文件公开-私有
of thing now he's got jigsaw coming in
现在他有拼图来了
and you can actually shield off or
您实际上可以屏蔽掉
actually just exposed parts that you
实际上只是暴露了你的零件
want other libraries to use so if I'm
希望其他图书馆使用，如果我
just doing my own library or creating a
只是做我自己的图书馆或创建一个
module why would I still want to do
模块为什么我仍然想做
private stuff and not just make
私人的东西，而不仅仅是
everything public and then shield it off
一切公开，然后将其屏蔽
by the module info I'm sorry I didn't
通过模块信息我很抱歉我没有
follow that so if I've got a library so
跟随那个，如果我有图书馆的话
I'm creating a module right right I've
我正在正确地创建一个模块
got old code under my own control yes
有旧代码由我自己控制
why would I still want to make stuff
我为什么还要做东西
private since I can shield off parcel
私人的，因为我可以屏蔽包裹
and I don't want anybody else to use
我不希望其他人使用
you're the only developer whoever works
您是唯一可以工作的开发人员
on this code do you trust yourself two
在此代码上，您是否相信自己两个
years from now probably no I mean I I
从现在开始的几年以后
don't trust myself from two years ago or
不要相信两年前的自己
two years from now I mean certainly if
从现在起两年后
you if you control all the code then
如果您控制所有代码，那么
yeah maybe you don't need to do anything
是的，也许您不需要做任何事情
okay but it you know as soon as one more
好的，但是你知道的越多越好
developer comes into play whether it's
开发人员是否参与其中
somebody in Europe your own organization
在欧洲有人自己的组织
or somebody maintaining some open source
或有人维护一些开源
thing that you depend on what life gets
你赖以生存的东西
riskier okay I have a counter question
风险更大，好吧，我有一个反问
for the room how many people in this
这个房间有多少人
room as Java coders have used the
Java程序员已经使用了
private key word to protect code from
私钥保护代码免受
yourself ya see exactly yeah
你自己，你明白了吗
accessibility modifier send a signal
辅助功能修改器发送信号
right you know they send a signal about
对，你知道他们发出一个关于
whether this is you know serving the
这是否你知道服务
code immediately adjacent to it the code
与之紧邻的代码
in a slightly larger circle or or the
在稍大的圆圈内，或
whole world and it's it's hard to keep
整个世界，很难保持
those in your head and that's why we put
那些在你的头上，这就是为什么我们把
them in the code um I neglected to have
我忽略的代码中有它们
us introduce ourselves but it might be
我们自我介绍，但这可能是
obvious anyway I'm mark Reinhold up with
无论如何，我都会标记Reinhold
the slug gun and marks the chief
子弹枪并标记首长
engineer I'm the jvm architect John rose
工程师，我是jvm架构师John rose
Brian gets language architect and we all
布莱恩（Brian）成为语言设计师，我们所有人
work for Oracle and for the most part we
为Oracle工作，在大多数情况下，我们
enjoy it believe it or not oh so poll
信不信由你喜欢它哦民意调查
question how many people have downloaded
询问有多少人下载了
and and played with an early access jdk
并与早期访问jdk一起玩
nine built did your existing code work
九个已建立，您现有的代码是否起作用
did it did it break did it break
打破了吗打破了吗
violently did you figure out why ask him
你猛烈地弄清楚了为什么问他
yeah well they're there they're catching
是的，他们在那里，他们正在追赶
up Remmy already has a built but that's
瑞米（Remmy）已经建好了，但是
caught up with that how many people have
赶上了多少人
downloaded and played with a jigsaw
下载并玩拼图游戏
early access did your existing code
抢先体验做了您现有的代码
break have you done downloaded the the
休息一下，您已经下载了
jigsaw EA within within the last two
最后两个内的拼图EA
weeks because it might be that more of
个星期，因为可能更多
your code broke sorry it's shifting
您的代码不好意思，它正在转移
ground bleeding edge any more questions
地面出血边缘还有其他问题
we should ask we are no wait we're
我们应该问我们不等我们
supposed to answer them yeah we're just
应该回答他们，是的，我们只是
here to answer questions we can ask
在这里回答我们可以问的问题
questions too I mean if nobody's going
问题也是我的意思是如果没人去
to ask please come up here
请问这里
so that means some discussions before
所以这意味着之前有一些讨论
about ahead of time compilation is a
关于提前编译是一个
part of Jillian coitus is whatever it's
吉利安性交的一部分是什么
used to be like committing old ways so
过去就像犯了老路
what's this state they're in ahead of
他们处于什么样的状态
time compilation right now we have a
时间编译现在我们有一个
project on going for the last couple
最后一对夫妇的项目
years on ahead of time compilation we're
提前几年编译我们
using Grall the Gras core which is an
使用Grall Gras核心
open source product as a project as a
开源产品作为项目
base we are able to compile ahead of
基础，我们能够提前进行编译
time the Java base module and you might
Java基本模块的时间，您可能
ask what's the benefit and we've learned
询问有什么好处，我们已经了解到
over the over these months a very
在过去的几个月中，
important rule of thumb which other
重要的经验法则
people who have experimented with aot
尝试过aot的人
have also found I think and that is that
也发现了我的想法，那就是
a ot gives you nearly all of its benefit
OT给您几乎所有的好处
in the first 100 milliseconds of program
在程序的前100毫秒
execution so there it turns out to be
执行，所以事实证明是
extremely difficult to find to find a
很难找到
way to beat the online jit after that
击败在线准时的方法
point I think there's probably things
我认为可能有事情
more that we can do there but the
我们可以在那里做更多的事情，但是
straightforward aot will basically shave
简单的aot基本上会刮胡子
off approximately up to a third maybe
大约下降三分之一
ten percent to a third of your first
百分之一到三分之一
hundred milliseconds of execution and
执行的一百毫秒
that sounds pretty pale and puny and
听起来很苍白，微弱，
maybe that's why you know maybe that's
也许那就是为什么你知道也许那是为什么
why Java got along without that for so
为什么Java没有那样相处
long but we we think it has some
很久了，但我们认为它有一些
particular uses for future
未来的特殊用途
implementations of Java where we're
我们所处的Java实现
actually taking an old technique out of
实际上是从旧技术
the labs of a self bootstrapping system
自我引导系统的实验室
implementing Java on top of Java and
在Java和Java之上实现Java
they're aot is a requirement rather than
他们是一个要求，而不是
a nice to have so that's our that's
很高兴有，这就是我们的
that's the reason we're doing a ot now
这就是我们现在做OT的原因
is we were looking forward to an
我们期待着一个
eventual project to to to replace more
最终要替换的项目
components of the JV j SJ to se stack
合资公司J SJ的组件
the jdk stack on using java as an
jdk堆栈上使用java作为
implementation language instead of c++
实现语言而不是c ++
or assembly code John said j2se he
或汇编代码John说j2se他
really meant java SE yes thank you sorry
真的是Java SE的意思，谢谢，对不起
and
和
and and you know comparing static to
而且您知道将静态与
dynamic compilation is a lot of people
动态编译的人很多
assume well compiling ahead of time is
假设提前做好编译是
better because you're not doing this
更好，因为您没有这样做
extra work at runtime but but in reality
在运行时进行额外的工作，但实际上
like everything else it's a trade-off
像其他一切一样，这是一个权衡
and so you're trading off compilation
所以你在权衡编译
quality against compilation time at
相对于编译时间的质量
runtime so dynamic compilers will always
运行时，因此动态编译器将始终
beat static compilers in terms of the
在静态方面胜过静态编译器
quality of the code they generate
他们生成的代码的质量
because they have more information with
因为他们有更多的信息
which to make better optimization
可以进行更好的优化
decisions so you know for a lot in
决定，所以您了解很多
previous attempts at a ot compilation
以前的ot编译尝试
people were always disappointed that the
人们总是失望的
aot compiled code was slower than the
aot编译的代码比
dynamically generated code it just you
动态生成的代码就在您身上
get to peak performance faster and so a
更快达到最佳性能，因此
OT really is mostly a startup play and
OT实际上主要是初创公司，
you know for programs that run for as
您知道运行的程序
long as seconds it's you know it's not
只要几秒钟，你就知道不是
actually that relevant and if you want
实际上相关，如果你想
to write a little program that starts up
编写一个启动的小程序
fires off a few packets and then shuts
触发一些数据包然后关闭
down you might use other languages today
下来，您今天可能会使用其他语言
for that already but we hope eventually
为此，但我们希望最终
as a ot becomes mature that we will be
随着OT变得成熟，我们将
able to write components like that in
能够在其中编写类似的组件
you know in Java and the there's there's
你知道在Java中有
early indications that that's quite
早期迹象表明那是相当
practical because some of you may have
实用，因为你们中有些人可能
seen some of the presentations by people
看了一些人的演讲
in the labs on technologies such as the
在诸如
substrate vm which is able to shrink
能够收缩的基材vm
down a hello world type job a program
你好世界级的工作程序
into a bundle about as small as a sea
像海一样小成一捆
program that starts up about as far as
程序可以启动到
as fast as a sea program so there isn't
像海上程序一样快，所以没有
there is a sort of extreme amount of
有一种极端的
work that you can do in the hundred
您可以在数百中完成的工作
millisecond x time scale and so I think
毫秒x时间刻度，所以我认为
we'll eventually we'll get there what
我们最终将到达那里
but we're you know we're just taking
但是我们你知道我们只是在服用
baby steps right now as far as the the
宝宝现在就走到
product is concerned but the labs
产品有关，但实验室
experiments look very promising and we
实验看起来很有希望，我们
expect within the next year to have some
期望在明年内有一些
some open source activity along this
一些开源活动
line
线
for the API such as unsafe that we don't
对于不安全的API，例如我们不
want to use anymore there's usually good
想要使用了，通常会很好
replacements for those that there aren't
替代那些没有的
any replacements planned as far as Oh
计划进行任何替换，直到哦
like son mis signal why not just make
像儿子一样发信号，为什么不让
those into api's and bless them as being
那些进入api并祝福他们
available to use or can we have a
可以使用或者我们可以
timescale for replacing them somehow so
更换它们的时间表
the general philosophy on this is laid
奠定了这一一般哲学
out in JEP 260 you know as we are we are
在JEP 260中，您知道我们是我们
gradually providing standard
逐步提供标准
functionality for much of what's in the
大部分功能
Sun misc packages and other unsupportive
Sun杂项软件包和其他不支持的软件包
things right of our handles which Paul
保罗正确处理的事情
sandoz is sitting the back has been
山德士正坐在后面
working on and handle many many of those
处理并处理许多这样的事情
cases but are we know there are a number
情况，但我们知道有很多
of critical api's like some has gone
关键api之类的东西已经消失了
Saif that lots of people depend on even
如果很多人甚至依靠
though they're technically unsupportive
尽管他们在技术上不支持
so they will be there until there are
所以他们会一直在那里直到
replacements and then they will stick
替换，然后他们会坚持
around until at least one major release
直到至少一个主要版本
after those replacements existed a
这些替换存在之后
question question from Twitter I think
我认为来自Twitter的问题
this is for Brian what are the chances
这对布莱恩来说是什么机会
of Jeff 286 which is local variable type
的Jeff 286是局部变量类型
inference making it into a JVM near me
推断使其进入我附近的JVM
soon this soon mean yeah it's kind of my
很快，这很快意味着是的，这是我的
question so if that's code for JD canine
问题，如果这是JD犬的代码
the chances are zero it was not ever
机会永远是零
part of the plan for nye and despite the
奈计划的一部分，尽管
article in the server side today which
今天在服务器端的文章
claimed that it was and despite the fact
声称是这样，尽管事实
that we at the keynote said several
我们在主题演讲中说
times this was not 49 but it's not the
时代不是49，但不是
world's biggest feature so using your
世界上最大的功能，因此使用
judgment about well it's not for nine
判断结果不是九点
but it's not huge you can think about
但是你可以考虑的并不多
what the implications that might be
这可能意味着什么
little it will be in some release
很少会发布
afternoon with it with a relief with a
下午与它与救济
number greater than nine probably
数字可能大于九
if you could limit your answers to the
如果您可以将答案限制在
java or oracle business and technical
Java或Oracle业务和技术
space for this question but what keeps
这个问题的空间，但保持不变
you guys awake at night at the moment
你们现在晚上都醒着
I'm not going going to comment on any
我不会对任何评论
business things that might keep me awake
可能让我醒着的商业事物
well what what keeps me coming to work
是什么让我上班
how about that is the fact that we have
那事实是我们有
an extraordinarily vibrant ecosystem for
一个极其活跃的生态系统
its built built by and for nerds like us
它是由像我们这样的书呆子建造的
that that runs a huge proportion of the
那占了很大一部分
world's computing and does so rather
世界的计算，而宁愿这样做
well and still has room for improvement
好，还有改进的空间
and the improvements look like they
和改进看起来像他们
would not only be beautiful and
不仅会很漂亮
satisfying to work with but also
满意的工作，但也
incredibly productive so what keeps me
令人难以置信的生产力，是什么让我
going is the the next 20 years of Java
Java的未来20年
dude oh yeah and then and amplify that I
花花公子哦，是的，然后放大我
would say that the the long-term road
会说长期的道路
map of the the set of the set of
集合的集合的地图
sensible improvements and enhancements
明智的改进和增强
that we can foresee now and have a
我们现在可以预见并有一个
pretty good idea of how to do and are
如何做的很好的主意
just quote a matter of Engineering is
只是引用一个工程问题是
better than it's ever been
比以往任何时候都更好
this is kind of a specific question but
这是一个特定的问题，但是
one of the things that slows down our
减慢我们速度的事情之一
vibrant Java ecosystem is a digital
充满活力的Java生态系统是数字
signature algorithm called RSASS a PSS
称为RSASS和PSS的签名算法
and so in Java 8 we recently upgraded to
因此在Java 8中，我们最近升级到了
a latest and greatest Java 8 I think
我认为最新最好的Java 8
update 66 I decided that that needed to
更新66，我认为这需要
be validated when using TLS 12 and it
使用TLS 12时需要验证
doesn't validate and I'm wondering if
没有验证，我想知道是否
there's any plan for support for that
有任何支持的计划
algorithm it's Microsoft's default pki
算法，这是微软的默认pki
cert algorithm oh that's a good one you
证书算法哦，这是一个很好的你
have stumped the panel sir whoa it is is
绊倒了面板先生，哇，是
this an algorithm for which there was
这是一个算法
already support no it support was added
已经支持不支持添加
in this in this eight update well it's
在这八次更新中，
kind of referred to in some of the Java
在某些Java中被提及
documentation it's there's a openjdk
文档中有一个openjdk
there's a there's a ticket for it jdk 80
那里有一张票80丹麦克朗
146 293 oh yeah that one yeah but why
146293哦，是的，但是为什么
didn't you say so that that may not they
你不是说不是
meant that may not help unless some of
意味着除非有一些
these googling back there for extra
这些谷歌搜索那里额外
information but it was kind of not clear
信息，但还不清楚
whether support would come for in jdk 9
jdk 9是否会提供支持
or ever do we have anybody from the
或曾经有来自
security team here Jeanette Sean yeah
安全小组在这里Jeanette Sean yeah
you want to find Sean Mullan or Joe or
您想要找到Sean Mullan或Joe或
Jeanette hun can probably answer answer
珍妮特·洪（Jeanette hun）可能会回答
this question or security dev security
这个问题或安全开发人员的安全性
Devon okay okay thank you
德文郡好的好的谢谢
weirdly kind of connected but not
奇怪的连接但不是
because of security but because of
因为安全，但是因为
release of features now we are getting
现在发布的功能
jigsaw and a more modular JDK is there a
拼图和更模块化的JDK
possibility for a more frequent release
释放频率更高的可能性
cycle of features in modules hmm
模块中功能的周期
fascinating question uh quite possibly
很有意思的问题
so one of the big reasons we're
所以我们的主要原因之一
modularizing the platform the JDK is in
模块化JDK所在的平台
fact to make it easier to evolve but
事实使它更容易发展，但是
maintain an evolved going forward at one
保持不断向前发展
might imagine no more a more rapid pace
可能再也想不到
we don't foresee any time in the near
我们不会在附近预见到任何时间
future having some sort of mix-and-match
未来会有某种混搭
of modules where you could take a base
可以作为基础的模块
module from JDK 9.1 and mix it with your
JDK 9.1中的模块并将其与您的
HTTP client module from JDK 9.4 and
JDK 9.4和更高版本的HTTP客户端模块
throw in a couple of 10 modules from jdk
从jdk投入几个10个模块
10 that becomes a support nightmare but
10变成了噩梦，但
definitely modularizing the platform
绝对模块化平台
going from that bowl of spaghetti if
如果要从那碗意大利面去
you've seen the ugly diagram to to the
您已经看到了丑陋的图表
fairly same model graph makes for a
完全相同的模型图使得
platform that we can evolve more more
我们可以进一步发展的平台
quickly because the components are
快速，因为组件是
actually identified and independent and
实际确定和独立
somewhat protected from each other
互相保护
hi so my company which might be
嗨，我的公司可能是
emblazoned all over the back of my
刻在我的背上
t-shirt of course has a java agent yes
T恤当然有Java代理了
which our java business depends on and a
我们的Java业务所依赖的
reliability problem emerges because at
出现可靠性问题是因为
the point in time that we transform
我们转变的时间点
classes we really just want to transform
我们真的只想转换的类
bytecode but we find ourselves tangled
字节码，但我们发现自己很纠结
up in the middle of a class load because
在上课的中间，因为
that's the way the instrumentation api
这就是检测API的方式
is currently implemented that we
目前已实施
intercept the class load there's another
拦截类负载还有另一个
framework that does a similar kind of
做类似的框架
thing but the instrumentation interface
东西，但仪器接口
is actually hooked to the just-in-time
实际上是即时的
so it's not actually the the the
所以它实际上不是
bytecode transformation is not actually
字节码转换实际上不是
done in the middle of somebody else's
在别人的中间做
class load that's already been resolved
已经解决的类负载
it's done later just before the
在稍后之前完成
just-in-time actually executing can you
准时实际执行可以吗
name this other frame workers yes
命名其他框架工人是
Lucille are yeah and the points they get
Lucille是的，他们得到的积分
out of frame work there's an entirely
超出框架的范围
different black work ok so thank you
不同的黑色作品好，所以谢谢
you're right so you meant something
你说得对，所以你的意思是
running on how I yet I didn't I didn't
以我还没有的方式运行
look into I didn't mean to be snide in
看着我不是故意
any case it's a little simpler in some
无论如何，在某些情况下它要简单一些
respect because they're not in the midst
尊重，因为他们不在中间
of a class load when they do the
他们做的时候
bytecode transformation and so they
字节码转换，所以他们
can't get tangled up in deadlock
无法陷入僵局
scenarios with badly written customer
客户写得不好的情况
custom class loaders and so on and so
定制类加载器等等
forth and the question I have is whether
来了，我的问题是
there's any possibility of evolving the
有可能发展
instrumentation API in a way that would
工具API
reduce the likelihood of the kinds of
减少这种可能性
very occasional very specialized issues
非常偶然的非常专业的问题
we see the long tail of reliability
我们看到可靠性的长尾巴
issues hmm good question um I don't
问题，嗯，好问题，嗯，我不
think that anybody anybody has has
认为任何人都有
thought deeply about improving that API
关于改进该API的深入思考
recently I'm thinking I'm thinking
最近我在想
j-link is the answer here at so 11 of
j-link是第11个答案
the one of the tools that that comes out
出现的工具之一
of JD canine and modularity is a link
JD canine和模块化是一个链接
time step so historically you compile
时间步长，从历史上看，您可以编译
java source code to java bytecode and
Java源代码转换为Java字节码和
then all linkage happens at runtime
然后所有链接都在运行时发生
and there are a lot of operations a lot
而且有很多操作
of optimizations that are sort of too
也有一些优化
early to do at compile time and as
尽早在编译时和
you're pointing out or a little bit late
你指出或有点晚
to be doing at runtime and so since Java
因为Java
hasn't historically had a link time
历史上没有链接时间
that's left you in kind of a you know a
那让你有点了解
limbo situation so Jay link is a tool
边缘局势，所以Jay Link是一个工具
that processes class files jar files etc
处理类文件，jar文件等
after build you know but before runtime
构建后，您知道但运行时之前
and we use J link to do all kinds of
我们使用J链接来做各种
things to produce custom images to strip
产生自定义图像以剥离的东西
debug symbols out to do byte code
调试符号以执行字节码
optimizations turn you know reflective
优化让您知道反思
look up into you know static you know
抬头看着你知道静态你知道
static references and for the sort of
静态引用和
bite good instrumentation that you want
咬你想要的好仪器
to do that seems like an ideal
这样做似乎很理想
application of jail Inc which has a
监狱公司的应用程序具有
plug-in architecture so you can define
插件架构，因此您可以定义
j-link transformations you know and and
您知道的j-link转换以及
that way it happens once offline at
这样一来，一旦离线
build time and then when the bike code
建立时间，然后当自行车代码
is loaded into the vm it's it's all
被加载到vm中就完成了
ready to go yeah so yes well there's one
准备好了，是的，好吧，有一个
proviso though Jay link only works with
尽管杰伊链接仅适用于
explicit modules if you have a pile of
显式模块（如果您有一堆）
jar files on the classpath today you
今天你在类路径上的jar文件
could probably apply similar strategy
可能会应用类似的策略
maybe and maybe rewrite them ahead of
也许并且也许提前重写它们
time but Jay link can't it can't pre
时间，但周杰伦链接不能做不到
link just random jar files because it's
链接只是随机的jar文件，因为
it's it's chaos yeah but you know in in
是的，是的，但是你知道
5-10 years time it might apply to a lot
5-10年的时间可能适用于很多
of code so the massive legacy code runs
代码，因此大量遗留代码可以运行
inside a massive recursive class loader
在大型递归类加载器中
in vacations and part of your problem is
在假期里，你的部分问题是
that its legacy but of course part of
它的遗产，但当然是
your value add is that you work on
您的增值之处在于您在工作
legacy so there's no easy answer I will
传统，所以没有简单的答案，我会
say that that Java doesn't really have a
说Java确实没有
just-in-time moment the way clr does
clr的即时方式
because they have a warmup period in
因为他们有一个热身期
possibly in the interpreter so you've
可能在口译员中，所以您已经
got to capture the byte codes really
必须捕获字节码
early but I think the right answer
提早但我认为正确的答案
long-term sort of the let's say the
长期来看
architectural right answer is to do
建筑的正确答案是要做
these sorts of transfer
这些转移
orms earlier rather than later and do
早些而不是晚些再做
them in a in a static setting and that's
他们在一个静态的设置，那就是
why we're that's one of the benefits of
为什么我们是那的好处之一
working with jay lincoln modules and
使用杰伊·林肯模块和
even a ot and some of the other features
甚至还有其他一些功能
like class data sharing were aiming to
就像班级数据共享旨在
be able to move more of the sort of Java
能够移动更多种类的Java
provisioning of application code into
将应用程序代码供应到
the before startup and that's where
在启动之前，那就是
that's where we would see improvements
那是我们看到改进的地方
being made rather than tweaking the
而不是调整
instrumentation or the agent stuff to to
仪器或代理商的东西
add more capabilities to do those kinds
添加更多功能来执行此类操作
of things statically in jail angkat and
监狱angkat中的静态事物
we're doing that even in jdk nine now
我们现在甚至在九丹麦克朗就做到了
it's a fruitful area to to work in yeah
这是一个富有成果的工作领域
thanks when I say we're doing it at
谢谢，当我说我们正在做
night I mean we're doing it in the
晚上，我的意思是我们正在
implementation for example method
示例方法的实现
handles are being spun statically where
手柄是静态旋转的
they used to be spun dynamically things
他们曾经是动态旋转的东西
like that yeah we use j-link of course
像那样，我们当然使用j-link
to build the JDK itself so yeah that's
构建JDK本身，是的
all yeah it does really need to work it
是的，它确实需要工作
works it does work it's cool okay
确实有效，很好
question from Twitter we probably each
来自Twitter的问题，我们可能每个人
have our own different answer biggest
有自己不同的答案
single Java regret if you could give you
如果您能给您一个Java遗憾
you know so much to choose from if you
你知道很多选择
go back in time what one thing would you
时光倒流你会做一件事
change I'm already on record with my
我已经在记录中
answer so i guess i have to say at its
回答，所以我想我不得不说
serialization and and not the concept of
序列化，而不是概念
serialization the approach to
序列化的方法
serialization which is a magic scraping
序列化是一种神奇的刮法
of fields that that allows d
允许d的字段
serialization to bypass constructors the
序列化绕过构造函数
gift that keeps on giving I so so many
礼物不断给我那么多
things that could be regrets are just
可能会后悔的事情只是
categorized for me as well that's the
对我来说也是如此
way it was at the time and we found the
当时的样子，我们发现了
optimal way to move through the
穿越的最佳方式
situation and get the best available out
情况并获得最好的机会
of the out of the opportunities but i
失去了机会，但我
would say that one thing that I regret
会说一件事我后悔
especially this year seeing how well
特别是今年看得如何
project Panama is turning out is that
巴拿马项目证明是
when I proposed it in 2005 it was
当我在2005年提出它时
heavily vetoed by the
严重否决了
the people that were running stuff then
然后那些正在运行东西的人
yep that was that was sad project Panama
是的，那是一个可悲的项目巴拿马
is really cool it's very panel was
真的很酷，非常面板
extremely cool so Brian's regret is is
非常酷，所以Brian的遗憾是
quite high on my list but I would say my
在我的名单上很高，但是我会说我的
top regret is in 12 or maybe one dot 3
最遗憾的是12点或一个点3
at the latest we should have done a
最迟我们应该做一个
module system you know everybody's life
你知道每个人的生活的模块系统
but those of us who work on the JDK and
但是我们这些从事JDK和
everybody uses it would it would be so
每个人都用它会是这样
much nicer right now because the DH is
现在好多了，因为DH是
this I don't know how many years project
这个我不知道要多少年
I've lost count of designing a module
我没有设计模块的数目
system that could be retrofitted on to
可以改装到的系统
all of the code in the JDK and the even
JDK和偶数中的所有代码
vaster you know I'm out of code out in
更大的范围内，您知道我没代码了
the world in a sensible way has been
世界以一种明智的方式
tough it's been fun and challenging but
艰难的是充满乐趣和挑战，但
we'd done it earlier if we've been
如果我们去过，我们会更早完成
better for everybody sir so the Twitter
先生，对每个人都更好
question actually trumped my question
这个问题比我的问题更重要
but I've changed it a little bit so mark
但是我做了一点修改
put up the Q&amp;A slide there i'm just
放一个问答幻灯片，我只是
saying that this is ask us anything
说这是问我们什么
about jdk is that okay you can ask the
关于jdk，好吧，你可以问
jdk art architect whatever question you
JDK艺术设计师，无论您有什么问题
cook all right so we might not answer it
没事做，所以我们可能不会回答
yeah or you might not not like the
是的，否则您可能不喜欢
answer this is the antidote of that
回答这是那个解药
question or so in the iphone style which
iPhone风格的问题
was the best release of java since Java
是自Java以来​​Java的最佳发行版
but the best release since 10
但是10以来的最佳发行
I think that has an easy answer the best
我认为最好的答案很简单
releases the one we're about to ship all
发布我们将要全部出货的那一款
that's true at any Franny at any given
任何给定的弗兰妮都是如此
point I'm I'm a pretty big fan of 88 was
我是88的忠实粉丝
it was very nice oh I'll do 82 yeah as a
很好，哦，我会做82次
side note we were we were amazed at the
旁注，我们当时对我们感到惊讶
adoption rate on eight well yeah it was
八口的采用率是的
faster than we've been in a long long
比我们长期以来的速度更快
long time we also know that the adoption
很长一段时间我们也知道收养
rate of nine will not be that fast
九的速度不会那么快
that's oh that's okay we're good with
哦，没关系，我们很好
that we've made peace with it
我们与之和平相处
there is a facility in Java in the class
在课堂上有Java的功能
loader to load the class is there any
加载程序加载类是否有
way I can unload the class yes you can
我可以卸载课程的方式是的，你可以
drop all references to it and to the
删除所有对其的引用以及对
class loader and to all objects that are
类加载器以及所有
instances about a local number manually
手动有关本地号码的实例
I to do it on my in my applications I
我在我的应用程序中做到这一点
had a different version of the product
产品有其他版本
so I spawned a new class loader with the
所以我产生了一个新的类加载器
new version of the job but at the same
新版本的工作，但同时
time because memory footprint is
时间，因为内存占用量是
increasing I have to say that i sat down
越来越多，我不得不说我坐下了
the previous one so how quickly I can
上一个那么快
close the URI class loader from the
从中关闭URI类加载器
previous one will it clean the memory
前一个会清除内存
hey you you cannot explicitly release
嘿，你不能明确释放
the class just as you cannot explicitly
就像您不能显式地
release an object yeah but you know
释放物体是的，但是你知道
because if you were to release a class
因为如果你要上课
you know try to try to unload the class
你知道尝试卸载课程
and there were still instances of that
而且仍然有这种情况
class around bad things would happen
围绕坏事上课
right so you have to make sure that no
对的，所以你必须确保没有
instances of that class are around and
该类的实例周围和
that's the job the garbage collector so
这就是垃圾收集器的工作
that garbage collector will eventually
那个垃圾收集器最终会
discover there are no instance of that
发现没有这种情况
class around and no instances of you
上课，没有你的实例
know no references to the class loader
不知道对类加载器的引用
and then the classloader week garbage
然后类加载器周垃圾
class yeah but there's a PIV to provide
是的，但是有PIV提供
to do the garbage collection right
做垃圾收集权
Georgie see something yeah you don't
乔治看到了你不知道的东西
ever want to call that no do not ever
曾经想称那不永远
call that yeah this system DC is is one
叫，是的，这个系统DC是一个
of those things that seemed like a good
那些看起来不错的东西
idea in Java 10 but is actually in in
Java 10中的想法，但实际上在
most in most cases as a disaster to use
在大多数情况下，这是灾难
because it does a you know a full a full
因为它做一个你知道一个完整的完整
garbage collection which can be very
垃圾收集可能非常
time consuming when in fact you don't
事实上，您不花时间
need to do a full garbage collection and
需要做一个完整的垃圾收集和
there many there there you know where
那里有很多，你知道哪里
many instances of people doing systems
人们在做系统的许多实例
off GC and libraries and you know you
关闭GC和库，您就知道了
know this is like I'm just a time bomb
知道这就像我只是一颗定时炸弹
hidden in the code and the people
隐藏在代码和人中
discover years later that the source of
发现几年后，
their performance problem is that they
他们的表现问题是
were using this XML library that
使用这个XML库
stupidly called system GC too often
经常把系统GC愚蠢地称为
there is another API point though for
还有一个API点
releasing everything it's called system
释放所有所谓的系统
exit no and I'm not just joking either
退出否，我也不只是在开玩笑
that is that is the way to really
那就是真正的方法
release everything like hot upgrade we
发布像热升级一样的一切
are doing so we need to replace the old
正在这样做，我们需要替换旧的
version of class with the new assoc you
新的assoc类的版本
you can't do that you can kind of fake
你做不到，你可以假冒
it out by using some
通过使用一些
higher level frameworks like I was GI
像我是GI这样的高级框架
that that the put you know they like
你知道他们喜欢的看跌期权
everything else you see you had a level
你看到的所有其他东西都有一个水平
of indirection so so there's sort of an
是间接的，所以有一种
abstract concept of a bundle and if you
捆绑的抽象概念，如果你
update the bundle then it's old class
更新包，然后是旧类
loader is is let go and a new one is
装载机是放开，新的是
spun up and then other bundles will
旋转，然后其他捆绑将
eventually refer to the new class loader
最终参考了新的类加载器
and that all works but it's an awful lot
而且一切正常，但是很多
of mechanism you know if you need it you
的机制，您知道是否需要
can use it but you know that's that's
可以使用它，但是你知道那就是
not how primitive class voters work in
不是原始阶级选民的工作方式
the platform thank you sure um let's see
该平台谢谢你，嗯，让我们看看
Twitter Brian any chance of currying
Twitter布赖恩有任何冒犯的机会
arguments and lambdas not something
论点和lambdas没什么
we're working on right now where we have
我们现在正在努力
other things that we're working on right
我们正在做的其他事情
now that we think are of greater value
现在我们认为具有更大的价值
such a diplomat good okay good idea or
这样的外交官好吧好主意，或者
bad idea well it it's it's just really
好主意，这是真的
really really really far from the 50
真的真的很远离50
most productivity-enhancing things we
我们最能提高生产力的事情
could be working on certainly I think
可能正在研究我肯定
it's more of a philosophical request
这更多是哲学上的要求
than a something that really makes a
比真正使
difference in terms of everyday
每天的差异
productivity and they're just so many
生产力，他们是如此之多
other things that would have more of an
其他东西会有更多的
impact yeah what what killer API that
影响是什么，什么杀手级API
hasn't been written yet would require
还没有写，将需要
currying above all else I don't think
最重要的是我不认为
there is one there are killer languages
有一种语言是杀手languages
that use currying but Java has enough of
使用currying但Java有足够的能力
its workarounds that it doesn't really
它不是真的解决方法
need them need currying apparently in
需要他们显然需要在
Scala you can do nice things with
Scala可以帮助您做得更好
currying so maybe maybe I'm wrong maybe
也许所以我错了
there is a killer application from Scala
Scala有一个杀手级应用
some killer API that could be moved into
一些杀手级的API可以移入
Java if only we had currying well and
Java，只要我们顺应一切，
you don't see it and to take an even
你看不到，甚至要均匀
more obvious example so how many people
比较明显的例子有多少人
here have like noticed that Java lambdas
这里已经注意到Java lambdas
can't call themselves I don't see every
不能自称我看不见
hand in the room going up there's two
把手放在上升的房间里有两个
yeah so you know one of the first lamb
是的，所以你知道第一个羊羔之一
to hack days that I did I you know and
破解我曾经知道的日子，
and it was with London jug with there
和那边的伦敦水罐一起
were a bunch of a bunch of academic
一堆学术
showed up and they like pitched hissy
出现了，他们喜欢变嘶哑
fits of like are you serious you calling
非常适合您打电话吗
this a lambda it can't even call itself
这个lambda，它甚至不能自称
you know you guys are dicks point it
你知道你们是鸡巴点
and this was an engineering trade off
这是工程上的权衡
the you know we were able to simplify
你知道我们能够简化
the semantics significantly by not you
语义明显不是你
know and not having to accommodate this
知道并且不必容纳这个
and it hasn't turned out to be a big
并没有证明它太大
deal right yes it would be nice to be
交易权是的，这将是很好
able to write factorial like you do in
能够像你一样写阶乘
the computer science textbooks as a
计算机科学教科书
recursive lambda but in reality in terms
递归lambda，但实际上
of getting in the way of the everyday
妨碍日常工作
job of java programmers it's a complete
Java程序员的工作很完整
non-issue so you know in a perfect world
没有问题，所以你知道在一个完美的世界
yes of course we'd have all these things
是的，我们当然会拥有所有这些东西
but it turns out that one can get an
但事实证明，一个人可以得到
awful lot of work done without them and
没有他们，很多工作就完成了，
you know all but two people in the room
你知道房间里只有两个人
haven't noticed so sometimes pragmatic
没注意到，所以有时很务实
trade-offs you know are pretty good what
您知道的权衡是很好的
make us Java most popular one of the
使我们成为Java最流行的工具之一
most a public language in the world why
世界上最公开的语言
is Java not the most popular language in
Java不是Java中最受欢迎的语言
the world yes I know if I think I think
世界是的，我知道我是否认为
he's asking why why is it one of why why
他在问为什么这是为什么之一
is it mmm because ya know I'm in when
是因为我知道我在什么时候
white job is so popular in the war oh
白色工作在战争中是如此受欢迎哦
why what made it success what made it
为什么成功使成功
successful well i mean the the the key
成功是关键
the core values of the platform from the
平台的核心价值来自
very beginning have proved very
一开始就证明非常
attractive to to a large number of
吸引大量
people readability compatibility of
人们的可读性兼容性
course i mean i'm blanking on the other
当然，我的意思是我要在其他方面空白
three right readability compatibility
三权可读性兼容性
productivity performance transparency
生产力绩效透明度
transparency compatibility is certainly
透明兼容性肯定是
a very you know possibly the biggest you
一个非常你可能知道最大的你
know the fact the fact that code from
知道事实，代码来自
many years ago in binary form still runs
许多年前仍以二进制形式运行
as i showed in the keynote i took swing
正如我在主题演讲中所展示的，
set to jar from jdk five and it runs
从jdk 5设置为jar并运行
just fine on on a jigsaw EA built that
在拼图EA上建立起来就很好了
that's a pretty powerful thing and it's
这是很强大的事情，
not something that you find in all
不是你在所有中找到的东西
platforms you know in some ecosystems
您在某些生态系统中了解的平台
like for example this one you know the
例如，您知道这个
nature of them is such that the the
他们的本质是这样的
dominant force in the ecosystem can
生态系统中的主导力量可以
force people to go through phases of
迫使人们经历以下阶段
income
收入
the changes and that actually works out
的变化，实际上是可行的
java the java ecosystem doesn't work
Java Java生态系统无法正常工作
that way so we've always tried to be
这样，我们一直试图成为
very responsible about evolving it that
对它的发展非常负责
also that kind of relates to another
也与另一种有关
question on Twitter do do you think that
在Twitter上提问，您认为
at some point Java will break
在某个时候Java会崩溃
compatibility in favor of faster and
兼容性，支持更快和
easier innovation yes I I think we are
更容易的创新是，我认为我们是
we are grab we're you know as I see it
我们很抢，我们知道你是谁
and I and I suspect like to call eggs
我和我怀疑喜欢叫鸡蛋
agree we're we're going through a slow
同意我们正在经历一个缓慢的过程
phase change where we are we are ready
我们准备就绪的阶段变化
to recognize that some things just don't
认识到有些事情只是不
belong there we're ready when we need to
属于那里，我们已经准备好在需要时
make forward progress to remove old
取得进步，以消除旧
things in in java SE 9 we're proposing
我们提出了Java SE 9中的东西
to remove for the first time ever we are
第一次移除我们
removing 6 methods I you know baby steps
删除6种我知道的方法
but but you but you have those six
但是你却只有那六个
methods were we're preventing a clean
我们防止清洁的方法
modularization of the platform if we
如果我们将平台模块化
kept those six methods then if you
保留这六个方法
wanted to use anything in the java.util
想要在java.util中使用任何东西
package you would all have to carry
你们都必须携带的包裹
around all of swing and awt that's not a
围绕所有秋千和awt，这不是
good solution an attorney you know and
一个好的解决方案，你认识的律师
we were careful about this we studied
我们对此研究非常谨慎
like all the jars we could find on maven
就像我们在行家中可以找到的所有罐子一样
central and elsewhere and found that
中央和其他地方，发现
these methods were actually very rarely
这些方法实际上很少
used so you know low-risk thing that
用过，所以你知道低风险的东西
we've even been very clear about it we
我们甚至对此非常清楚
gave notice when when job seh shipped
作业何时发货时发出通知
thinking of these six methods our
考虑这六种方法
history we've removed a few other
历史我们删除了其他一些
mechanisms in in in jdk nine that were
在JDK 9中的机制是
either standard and not and rarely used
要么是标准的，而不是，很少使用
or non-standard and rarely used and
或非标准且很少使用
these are all documented in in the
这些都记录在
various jep's and of course in nine
各种吉普车，当然还有九个
we're also we are also encapsulating
我们也正在封装
most jdk internal api's now from a
现在大多数jdk内部api来自
purist standpoint that is not an
纯粹的立场不是
incompatibility because after all you
不兼容，因为毕竟你
should only be using the standard API
应该只使用标准API
drain and nobody here uses non standard
流失，这里没有人使用非标准
a PSP right oh sorry you know so so it
一个PSP，对不起，您知道吗
yeah it is a it is a practical and
是的，这是实用的
compatibility
兼容性
but we've we've tried hard to
但是我们已经尽力了
communicate all that and provide tools
交流所有内容并提供工具
to to help people move beyond it and
帮助人们超越它
explain the reasons for it because we
解释原因，因为我们
know that for you know in some cases it
知道在某些情况下
will be painful you know and further
你知道会更痛苦
down the road I can imagine entire
我可以想象整个
subsystems perhaps being jettisoned from
子系统可能被抛弃
java SE do we really need to carry
Java SE我们真的需要携带吗
around jax-ws and jack's b and korba
围绕jax-ws和jack的b和korba
very useful to some people but do they
对某些人非常有用，但是他们
actually have to be part of SE mmm maybe
实际上必须是SE mmm的一部分
not so you guys wanted to refund
不是，你们想退款
compatible well I want to go back to the
兼容好，我想回到
previous question for a second and then
前一个问题一秒钟，然后
already found compatibility so iiii
已经发现兼容性，所以我
think the you know one of the
认为你知道其中之一
fundamental things that's made java so
Java的基本要素
successful is its commitment to
成功是其对
unobtrusive safety right so if you
不打扰的安全性，所以如果您
compare java to what was around before
比较Java与之前的情况
then which was mostly see there were a
然后大部分看到的是
lot of there were a lot of aspects where
很多很多方面
you had to manage safety yourself you
你必须自己管理安全
have to manage pointer safety you had to
必须管理指针安全
manage type safety you had to manage
管理您必须管理的类型安全
memory safety and java managed to take
内存安全和Java设法采取
these responsibilities away from the
这些责任从
program in a way where you didn't really
以一种您并不真正喜欢的方式进行编程
miss them and you had the the runtime
想念他们，你有运行时
you know i'm doing garbage collection
你知道我在做垃圾收集
for you you had you know a somewhat
因为你，你知道一些
stronger type system which got stronger
更强大的类型系统
you know further over over time you you
随着时间的流逝，您会更加了解
can't munge a pointer into an int you
无法将指针插入int中
know that you know the platform keeps
知道你知道平台保持
you from doing that so there are entire
你这样做，所以整个
categories of bugs that you just can't
您无法做到的错误类别
make in java and if you're not wasting
用java制作，如果你没有浪费
energy avoiding we're chasing down those
避免我们追逐那些精力的人
bugs you can focus that energy on more
您可以将精力集中在更多的错误
valuable activities and i think having
有价值的活动，我认为
found that balance of unobtrusive safety
发现平衡的安全性
i think was kind of the secret sauce and
我认为这是一种秘密的调味料
they're like any other success there was
他们就像其他任何成功一样
also a little bit of luck it was the
也有点运气是
right thing at the right time and we had
在正确的时间正确的事情，我们有
another secret sauce the thing that i
另一个秘诀就是我
have come to value even more over the
变得更加有价值
years is the quality of the original
岁月是原始的质量
specifications which has been maintained
保持的规格
but if you if you look at the at the
但是如果你看看
Java language spec you and you and you
Java语言规范您和您以及您
learn to lean on it and to
学会依靠它并
implement it and look for all the corner
实施并寻找所有角落
cases and how they're documented it is I
案例及其记录方式是我
think it's that I think it's maybe the
认为这是我认为可能是
best programming spec programming
最佳编程规范编程
language spec ever written it certainly
语言规范肯定写过
is in it's in the top ten got to be it's
在它的前十名中
in the top five yeah and and and you
在前五名中
look at the authors gosling steel joy
看看作者高斯林的喜悦
they put in a lot of time and effort
他们投入了大量时间和精力
into doing it and and it's it's been a
这样做，这是一个
gift to millions of people their
给数百万人的礼物
successors have carried the torch well
接班人的火炬传递很好
because they have awesomely care that
因为他们非常关心
are huge job Alex was here he's one of
Alex的工作非常艰巨，他是其中之一
the successors but he's next door
继任者，但他在隔壁
talking about modules and likewise with
谈论模块，同样
the with the jvm specification which was
与JVM规范是
started by Tim Lindholm beautiful work
由蒂姆·林德霍尔姆（Tim Lindholm）发起美丽的工作
and and and and work that was not
和and and and work不是
perfect nothing nothing's ever quite
完美无所不能
perfect but was very strong as a
完美，但作为一个非常强大
foundation for building something that
建立东西的基础
would be compatible something so
会兼容的东西，所以
compatible that you could do clean room
兼容，你可以做洁净室
implementations of it there iBM has made
iBM已在其中实施
a business and Oracle made a business
一家公司，甲骨文做了一家公司
aside from hospital with J rocket doing
除了用J火箭做的医院
a cleanroom implementation based on the
基于
specs it's very difficult to find a
规格很难找到
similar success for a specification like
类似的规范取得了类似的成功
that
那
so at the session a couple of years ago
所以在几年前的会议上
one of the questions that got a lot of
有很多问题之一
interest was the prospect of using utf-8
感兴趣的是使用utf-8的前景
is the default platform encoding is
是默认的平台编码是
there any progress on that or new
在那个或新的上有任何进展
obstacles that you found in moving
您在移动中发现的障碍
towards that glorious future thank you
走向光荣的未来，谢谢
for the reminder I'm not sure anybody's
提醒一下，我不确定有人
yeah no no I I'm extremely sympathetic I
是的，不，我非常同情我
don't think anybody has looked at that
不要以为有人看过
recently what you know what one could
最近你知道什么可以
say that if we're going to do that nines
说如果我们要去做那个九
the release to do it because we're
发布是因为我们
breaking everything else anyway right
反正一切都打破了
yeah thanks for the reminder alas the
是的，谢谢你的提醒
amount of utf-8 text in the world is
世界上utf-8文本的数量是
just increasing particularly with emojis
只是随着表情符号而增加
and the default platform in coatings
和涂料的默认平台
particularly on Windows or the 88 51 yet
特别是在Windows或88 51上
just aren't the right choice because
只是不正​​确的选择，因为
utf-8 Texas is almost all of the Texas
utf-8 Texas几乎是整个德克萨斯州
in the world now yeah no I mean hey I'm
在这个世界上，是的，不是，我是说，嘿，我是
nus utf-8 all the time how many people
nus utf-8一直有多少人
in this room consciously avoid utf-8 as
在这个房间里有意识地避免使用utf-8，因为
a platform encoding when they when they
当他们何时他们平台编码
launched Java waiting Craig 0 all right
启动Java等待Craig 0好的
well that's a data point yep
好吧，这是一个数据点
you can ask one question more question
你可以再问一个问题
so you get back in line yeah okay so how
所以你回来排队，好吧，怎么
do you stay current with technology
您了解最新技术吗
continue learning more like what do you
继续学习像你一样
do do that it's overwhelming talk to as
做到这一点与
many people as we can who are not
我们可以的很多人
involved in our own little bubble
参与我们自己的小泡沫
ecosystem read everything we can watch
生态系统读取了我们可以观看的所有内容
conference videos it's it is a lot of
会议视频，这是很多
information to process but you just have
要处理的信息，但您只有
to decide to be open to it because it's
决定对它开放，因为
so easy to focus on that which you're an
很容易专注于您
expert in and miss everything that's
专家，错过一切
going on outside and so you really have
在外面，所以你真的有
to make a conscious effort to broaden
有意识地努力扩大
your input sources and make time for
您的输入源并腾出时间
them at multiple scales so learn what
他们在多个层面上，所以学习什么
your colleagues are doing down the
你的同事正在做
hallway learn what your colleagues at
走廊了解您的同事在
they across the ecosystem are doing
他们遍布整个生态系统
learn what competitors are doing make
了解竞争对手在做什么
friends with your competitors and then
与您的竞争对手成为朋友，然后
learn what people that you don't
了解你不认识的人
normally cross paths with they're doing
他们通常会越过路径
and then since we are in computing go
然后既然我们从事计算
read some math and some science and so
阅读一些数学和一些科学知识等等
this year I read a couple books by
今年我读了几本书
Raymond Smolyan on mathematical logic
Raymond Smolyan谈数学逻辑
just a brilliant refresh on that stuff
只是对这些东西的精彩更新
that it gave me fresh you know fresh
它给了我新鲜，你知道新鲜
eyes for what I do so it works at
盯着我所做的事情
multiple scales yeah I I often Mei that
多个音阶，是的，二常梅
I I make a regular point of trying to
II尽力尝试
keep up with the programming language
跟上编程语言
academic research that's kind of where I
我的学术研究
came from is hard there's an awful lot
来自很难有很多
to read there's an awful lot of it that
读到很多
I just don't understand anymore but but
我只是不明白了，但是
but but it's out there and another thing
但是它在那里，还有另一件事
I found helpful is I occasionally go
我发现有帮助是我偶尔去
back and reread papers that I read 30
返回并重读我读过的论文30
years ago to sort of get re-inspire by
多年前被重新激发
you know what whatever beauty and
你知道什么美丽，
clarity I found at that time I think
我当时发现的清晰度
probably every every five or six years I
大概每五六年一次
go back and read the steel in Sussman
回去读萨斯曼的钢铁
lambda papers there they're just you
lambda文件在那里，他们就是你
know golden keys to so many things
知道很多事情的金钥匙
what are the chances of type inference
类型推断的机会是什么
for a local method for method return
用于方法返回的本地方法
values and maybe for relieving us from
价值观，也许是为了减轻我们的负担
the semicolon that's two questions so
分号是两个问题，所以
you'll have to go back in the line for
您必须回到生产线
the second question type inference for
第二个问题类型推断
method return values is extremely
方法的返回值极高
unlikely and the reason for that is with
不太可能，原因是
the exception of private methods you
私有方法的例外
know methods are part of your API and
知道方法是您的API的一部分，并且
there's a binary compatibility
有二进制兼容性
consideration you don't want the return
考虑你不想退货
type to subtly change just because you
键入仅因您而微妙的更改
change the body of your implementation
更改实施主体
and now all of a sudden you're
现在突然之间
programming / no longer links because
编程/不再链接，因为
some other client that called your
其他一些打电话给您的客户
method thought the return type was this
方法以为返回类型是这个
embeds that signature in the class file
将该签名嵌入到类文件中
and now you know the signature has
现在您知道签名了
changed arguably that's not an issue for
可以改变，这不是问题
private methods but that means that then
私有方法，但这意味着
refactoring a method from private to
将方法从私有重构为
non-private you know is you know is a
非私有，你知道吗，你知道是一个
less easy refactoring the short answer
重构简短答案不太容易
is never going to happen now I'm for
现在永远不会发生
philosophical reasons and the semicolons
哲学原因和分号
so be serious
所以要认真
that's both the short and the long
这既是短期的，也是长期的
answer hit there's there are the list of
答案是有的列表
things that are more important to work
对工作更重要的事情
on the mat is virtually infinite there
在垫子上实际上是无限的
is a field where colon relief is
是结肠缓解的领域
important but it's medical so um given
很重要，但是医学上
your greatest regrets and the the
您最大的遗憾和
likelihood that Java could break
Java可能崩溃的可能性
compatibility of things could we ever
事物的兼容性，我们永远可以
see a new serialization mechanism and
看到一个新的序列化机制，
removals of the current joyful
当前快乐的消除
serialization which yeah it's certainly
序列化，是的，肯定是
quite possible that serialization can
序列化很有可能
improve it seems unlikely that we could
改善似乎不太可能
fully get rid of the existing
完全摆脱现有
serialization mechanism because there
序列化机制，因为那里
are situations that basically won't
基本上是不会的情况
serialize under anything but the current
除了当前以外的任何东西序列化
situation so we can't necessarily take
情况，所以我们不一定要采取
away the existing mechanism if we can't
如果我们不能解决现有的机制
replace it with something that is you
用你那东西代替
know compatible across the board that
知道全面兼容
said you know we've been making you know
说你知道我们一直在让你知道
a certain certain amount of progress in
在一定程度上的进步
identifying a serialization mechanism
识别序列化机制
that is safer easier to reason about
这样更容易推理
results in smaller object streams to
导致较小的对象流
which code could migrate and and we
哪些代码可以迁移，我们
think that's probably about the best we
认为这可能是我们最好的
could do but it's definitely something
可以做到，但这绝对是
we want to do I'll be more aggressive
我们想做的我会更加积极
than that I want to take it out and
比我想要拿出来的
shoot it one day one once we've had a
有一天，有一天就要拍摄一次
viable replacement for you know ninety
你知道可行的替代品
eight percent of the use cases I just
我只用了8％的用例
it's just the number of security
这只是安全性的数字
vulnerabilities we had to fix because
我们必须修复的漏洞
that mechanism is just too painful if
这种机制太痛苦了，如果
you look at serialization what it really
你看序列化到底是什么
amounts to is a secret contorted way of
等于是一种秘密的扭曲方式
adding new constructors to two classes
向两个类添加新的构造函数
sometimes undeclared and
有时未声明，
that that just doesn't work very well
那只是不能很好地工作
with any other part of Java's workflow
与Java工作流程的任何其他部分
so what what we what we need is some way
所以我们需要的是某种方式
of declaring constructors in a much more
在更多的方面声明构造函数
disciplined and reviewable auditable way
纪律严明和可审核的审核方式
and then for the other end of the
然后在另一端
equation coke instructors that that can
等式可乐教练，可以
take apart an object into the operands
将对象分解为操作数
to the constructors and and so that you
给建设者，这样你
know there's there's ways ways to do
知道有办法做
this and the way we have now is
这就是我们现在拥有的方式
incredibly contorted and low-level and
令人难以置信的扭曲和低级
impossible to understand but you know
无法理解，但你知道
everybody who's tried to do this nose of
每个试图做这个鼻子的人
course they want to be able to take an
当然，他们希望能够接受
object apart into its contents and then
将对象分解成其内容，然后
put it back together but that's a that's
放回去，但这是一个
a that's a handshake and a process that
这是一个握手和一个过程，
the author of the class needs needs more
班级的作者需要更多
control over or there's never going to
控制或永远不会
be any security yeah I'd like to remind
是的，我想提醒一下
everyone that one other reason why Java
每个人，为什么Java的另一个原因
is so insanely popular it has always
如此疯狂地受欢迎
been the very high quality of its
一直是它的高品质
libraries from the very beginning when I
从一开始我就图书馆
came to job as an application programmer
出任应用程序程序员
and that was one of the things that drew
那是吸引人的事情之一
me and that's still what draws people
我，那仍然吸引着人们
from other languages where it's often
来自其他经常使用的语言
very difficult to find a deep set of
很难找到深层次的
standard libraries such as in C++ for
标准库，例如C ++中的
example or where there are so many
例子或那里有很多
libraries to choose from all of varying
库供您选择
quality of implementation and languages
执行质量和语言
the children who name a name such as
诸如以下名字的孩子
JavaScript where this is something that
JavaScript，这就是
Java really excels in so I wanted to
Java确实擅长，所以我想
bring up that utf-8 remark that came and
提出来的utf-8言论，
turned that a little bit to the true
把那变成了事实
java.lang.string nowadays javed erlanger
时下java.lang.string javed erlanger
string as of java 9 is no longer a
从Java 9开始的字符串不再是
sequence of 16-bit core values
16位核心值的序列
internally the library however still
内部图书馆，但仍然
exposes this fiction and it is super
揭露了这个小说，它是超级的
inconvenient for developers who more
给更多的开发人员带来不便
more run into characters that require
更多遇到需要的字符
two 16-bit core values to be represented
要表示的两个16位核心值
the only thing that one can do right now
现在唯一可以做的
so you can turn a string into a stream
这样就可以将字符串转换为流
of the Unicode code points which is nice
Unicode代码点，这很好
it would be nicer if one could also
如果可以的话也更好
easily put it back it's not pretty right
轻松地放回去，这不是很正确
now it would be even nicer if the API
现在如果API更好了
cleaned up to present a string as a
清理以将字符串显示为
sequence of what it actually is is there
实际存在的顺序
yeah is that something that someone is
是的，有人在
looking at so going back to that regrets
看着所以回到那个遗憾
question using utf-16 ucs-2 as as the
问题使用utf-16 ucs-2作为
native encoding that's it's in my top 10
本机编码就是我的前十名
I don't think it's in my top five but
我认为这不是我的前五名，但
it's definitely one of those things
这绝对是其中之一
where you know it was a it was actually
你知道那是一个事实
a controversial decision at the time it
当时有争议的决定
was it was seen as very forward-looking
被认为是非常前瞻的
and pious 16 bits it's gonna be plenty
虔诚的16位会足够
right now we've heard we've heard that
现在我们听说过
before on in so many other dimensions
在其他许多方面之前
money yeah yeah 600 point I don't know
钱是600点我不知道
introducing another string abstraction
引入另一个字符串抽象
I've seen this happen in other languages
我已经看到这种情况发生在其他语言中
and it's extraordinarily painful i think
我觉得这非常痛苦
in hacen haskell there are two different
在哈森哈斯克尔，有两个不同的地方
two or three different string types that
两种或三种不同的字符串类型
are commonly used and fighting a Python
常用和对抗Python
is that has always had this weird
是那一直有这个怪异
distinction between you know strings and
你知道字符串和
sequence sequences of characters i I'd
我想要的字符序列
love dived love to see a better string
爱潜入了爱，看到了更好的弦
abstraction that internally allowed to
内部允许的抽象
utf-8 that provided you you the ability
utf-8为您提供了能力
to do arbitrary indexing but in some
做任意索引但在某些情况下
cases may be made it you know a log cost
您知道日志成本的情况下可能会发生
rather than a constant cost no it's not
而不是不变的成本，不是
actually well pretty modular code points
实际上很好的模块化代码点
but anyway it's it's it if your jobs
但无论如何，就是你的工作
ever had value types then there could be
曾经有过价值类型，那么可能会有
a data type for code point if
代码点的数据类型，如果
hypothetically speaking at ever had
假设说过
which would be the basis for a additions
这将是添加的基础
to the string API if that would be more
到字符串API，如果更多的话
convenient for programmers to use
方便程序员使用
without the cost of boxing so in that
没有拳击费用，因此
hypothetical future things might be
假设未来的事情可能是
better
更好
mm-hmm part of the problem is that we
嗯，问题的一部分是我们
ask that people use the indexed act care
要求人们使用索引行为护理
at accessors are treated like a raise
在访问者被视为加薪
but stringz are really concatenate able
但stringz确实可以连接
lot logically concatenate able symbols
很多在逻辑上将可连接符号连接
symbol sequences and so if you if you're
符号序列等等，如果您
willing to back off and treat them as
愿意退缩并将其视为
streams like you observed then you have
像你观察到的那样流，那么你有
a more natural way of getting code
一种更自然的代码获取方式
points out of them but if as long as we
指出他们，但只要我们
supply classic c-style for loops and
提供经典的C风格的循环和
iteration that uses i and i plus plus
使用i和i plus的迭代
and you know get get element at I it's
而且你知道在我那里得到get元素
there's going to be a severe performance
将会有严重的表现
problem with with allowing strings to
字符串允许的问题
contain anything I think anything other
包含我认为其他任何东西
than a fixed size element so we're we're
而不是固定大小的元素，所以我们
moving away from the old for loop but
远离旧的for循环，但
it's still it still tends to hold hold
它仍然倾向于保持住
us back on the decisions we can make
我们回到可以做的决定上
about about data structures especially
关于数据结构，尤其是
the one that's at the center like string
像字符串一样居中的那个
any data structure at the center Verity
Verity中心的任何数据结构
like stringer array it's very hard to
像纵梁数组，很难
evolve that what's your opinion on
发展您的看法
spring framework and in particular like
春天的框架，特别是喜欢
do you feel like it's not needed because
您是否觉得不需要，因为
Java can do all of that already or do
Java可以做到所有这些事情，或者可以做到
you feel like it's a good way to you
你觉得这是对你的好方法
know simplify things and kind of
知道简化事情和那种
improved Java language which framework
改进了Java语言的框架
spring Osprey blue it's a framework some
春天的鱼鹰蓝这是一些框架
people find find it useful it Brian I
人们发现它很有用Brian I
think you know more about it them yeah I
我以为你对它了解更多，是的，我
mean I I think application level
均值II认为应用程序级别
frameworks work at a very different
框架的工作方式截然不同
level than language does right so are
比语言水平高是正确的
you know our job as language and
你知道我们的语言工作
platform designers is to provide the
平台设计者将提供
sensible set of primitives and
明智的原语集和
programming model in which you can
您可以在其中编程的模型
express you know the things that you
表达你对你的了解
want to express both applications and
想要同时表达申请和
frameworks but you know frameworks the
框架，但您知道框架
role of frameworks is to abstract out
框架的作用是抽象
common application tasks you know to it
您知道的常见应用程序任务
you know we eliminate redundancy and
您知道我们消除了冗余，
improve reliability applications and you
改善可靠性应用，您
know that's perfectly since
知道那完全是因为
thing to do up at that level but you
在那个级别上要做的事情，但是你
know down at our level that's you know
知道我们的水平，就是
it's all just application up there from
都是从那里开始的应用程序
our perspective it's really important
我们的观点非常重要
but you know from where we sit you know
但是你知道我们坐在哪里
whether it's spring you know Java EE you
是否是春天，您知道Java EE吗
know time Tommy whatever I it's it's
知道时间汤米，无论我是什么
stuff up there and then we have to make
那里的东西，然后我们必须
it work well but sometimes you have to
它运作良好，但有时您必须
put in hooks to make frameworks work
挂上钩以使框架正常工作
well in other words a framework can be
换句话说，框架可以是
at first written on top of Java
首先写在Java之上
unmodified but once in a while you find
未修改，但偶尔会发现
places where like maybe hooks for
像钩子一样的地方
hibernation or something like that yeah
冬眠之类的
we you know at that point what needs to
我们知道那时您需要做什么
happen is that the framework people need
发生的是人们需要的框架
to engage us and say you know if you
吸引我们，说您知道您是否
were able to give us these hooks here
能够在这里给我们这些钩子
then we could make our lives together
然后我们可以一起生活
much better as indeed they have and they
他们的确好得多，他们
do that only times out here so in a sort
这样做只是在这里超时，所以有点
of a forward-looking example of that
一个前瞻性的例子
would be we want to be able to code
是我们想要能够编码
without what I call dinosaur so many
没有这么多我称之为恐龙的恐龙
dinosaur threads in our applications we
恐龙线程在我们的应用中我们
want a reactive programming model where
想要一个反应式编程模型
there's if events that trigger other
如果有事件触发其他
events and you don't have to have a
活动，而您不必
multi megabyte thread pulled along
多兆字节线程
behind you and so in order to do that
在你身后，所以为了做到这一点
you can you can use Java threads to
您可以使用Java线程
emulate actors and reaction points but
模拟演员和反应点，但
they they have costs and so maybe there
他们有成本，所以也许在那里
are some things we can do in the in the
我们可以在
in Java in the future which would allow
在将来的Java中
reactive frameworks can run more
反应性框架可以运行得更多
efficiently on top of Java so there are
有效地在Java之上，所以有
there are I would say there are lots of
我会说有很多
potential cut points down into the into
潜在的削减点下降到
the system which we you know need to
您所需要的系统
develop alongside our friends that are
与我们的朋友一起发展
building on top
建立在顶层
I'd like to ask you personally while I
我想问你一个人
de tool editors you use for editing Java
用于编辑Java的de工具编辑器
and why you choose those so I'm a big
以及为什么选择这些，所以我很大
IntelliJ fan i've been using IntelliJ
我一直在使用IntelliJ的IntelliJ风扇
since version two of their product which
从他们产品的第二版开始
is probably like 16 17 years ago or so
大概是16 17年前
at this point it's by far the best Java
在这一点上，它是迄今为止最好的Java
ID I mean I've tried i cried them all
ID我的意思是我尝试了我都哭了
including many of them that are out of
包括其中许多
business and there's no comparison in
业务，没有可比之处
order emacs IntelliJ and netbeans and
订购emacs IntelliJ和netbeans以及
you know if you want the bits right
你知道你是否想要正确的位
there in your fingers and you want to
你的手指在那里，你想
build a write macros that work on the
建立可在
bits and emacs is your friend it's it's
位和emacs是您的朋友，是的
the it's the hackers multi-tool yep
这是黑客的多功能工具
emacs it's wired into my fingers I've
emacs它已连接到我的手指中
been using it since sometime in the late
从后期开始一直在使用它
1970s you know occasionally NetBeans if
1970年代，您偶尔会知道NetBeans是否
I need to you know make a GUI or
我需要您知道制作GUI或
something but that in my lack of work
有些东西，但是由于我缺乏工作
that's pretty fair any chance to see in
这是很公平的机会
the future of shorter release cycles or
较短发布周期的未来或
minors and majors or something that do
未成年人和专业或做某事
go resulting more agility oh sure
可以带来更大的敏捷性哦
there's a chance what should that's so
有机会那应该是什么
that's actually an interesting question
这实际上是一个有趣的问题
so we we spend a lot of time thinking
所以我们花很多时间思考
about how long the release cycle is you
关于您的发布周期是多长时间
ought to be we look historically at how
应该是我们历史上看
long has it been in the past and of
过去和过去
course it's been highly variable
当然变化很大
sometimes for problems that are not
有时是因为不是
engineering problem problems at all but
工程问题，但根本没有问题
you know corporations merging and stuff
你知道公司合并和东西
like that what is the optimal cycle I
那样的最佳周期是多少
think something that we definitely want
想一些我们绝对想要的东西
to look at especially given the
尤其考虑到
experience of nine being this feature
九经验是这个功能
driven driven release is you know would
驱动驱动发布是您知道吗
would the platform with the wider
将平台与更广泛
community be best served by a more rapid
更快地为社区服务最好
release cycle that had a strict you know
您知道严格的发布周期
a really strict train model which was
一个非常严格的火车模型
just okay every year we're going to ship
每年我们都可以运送
at this time if your features ready you
目前，如果您的功能已经准备就绪，
know six seven months before then you go
知道六个七个月，然后你去
in and if it's not ready then you just
进去，如果还没准备好，那你就
wait so that's something you know we've
等一下，这就是你知道的
already done some thinking about will we
已经做了一些思考，我们会
switch to it I have no idea I'd be
切换到它我不知道我会成为
curious to know how you know it's always
好奇地知道你怎么一直知道
been our sense that a yearly cadence
我们的感觉是每年的节奏
would be too fast for a fair number of
对于相当数量的人来说太快了
users in the ecosystem lot you know lots
生态系统中的用户很多您知道很多
of we we here we here both directly and
我们在这里我们直接在这里和
anecdotally lighting a lots of companies
有趣地点燃了许多公司
they only know they've got big
他们只知道自己变得很大
deployments they only want to have to
他们只需要部署
test and qualify everything once every
一次测试并验证所有内容
two or three years so if you were gonna
两三年，如果你要
ship a new version of java SE every year
每年都会发布新版本的Java SE
they would just skip you know skip
他们只是跳过你知道跳过
versions and that would be bad and so I
版本，那将是不好的，所以我
don't know so I mean how many people
不知道，所以我的意思是有多少人
would like a yearly dearly cadence
想要每年一次的节奏
strict strict strict train model like
严格严格严格火车模型喜欢
you know like eclipse and a number
你知道像日食和数字
number of other projects do six seven
其他项目数量做六七
how many people prefer a feature driven
有多少人喜欢功能驱动型
model where there are one or maybe a
模型中有一个或一个
handful of big features and feature
少数重要功能
doesn't ship until those are done
在完成这些操作之前不发货
interesting day within fifty percent
有趣的一天，百分之五十
interesting data thank you i will not
有趣的数据，谢谢，我不会
predict the future what are the top
预测未来是什么
things you'd want to remove from java
您想从Java中删除的东西
like your top thing mark already named
就像您的头号商标已经命名
his yeah i think we are we already
是的，我想我们已经到了
answered that question bigger biggest
回答了这个最大的问题
regret I I would like to I we are so
很遗憾，二世想我，我们是如此
concerned with compatibility because we
关注兼容性，因为我们
don't want to break trust with the whole
不想破坏整体信任
ecosystem right so removing stuff is
生态系统是正确的，所以删除东西是
really difficult so if you ask what do
真的很难，所以如果你问做什么
we want to remove that's like an idol
我们想删除那就像一个偶像
Idol dream but there are things we want
偶像梦，但我们想要一些东西
to supplant too we want people there are
也要取代我们我们希望有人
items which we want people to stop using
我们希望人们停止使用的物品
so much and use better things
这么多，用更好的东西
serialization has been mentioned already
已经提到了序列化
I would say I mentioned the the old
我会说我提到了旧的
fashioned for loop I'd like to see less
老式的循环我想少看
use of that can't remove it but I'd like
使用它不能将其删除，但我想
to see it streams or the new style for
看到它的流或新样式
loop or a new new for loop that sort of
循环或新的for循环
his scream like that that would be
那样的尖叫会是
better that would be something I'd like
更好的是我想要的东西
to use to supplant the old for loop and
用于取代旧的for循环和
even more important but in a similar
甚至更重要，但类似
vein another another killer of program
成为另一个程序杀手
abstraction and parallel lies ability is
抽象和平行说谎的能力是
mutability mutability at by default i
可变性默认情况下，可变性i
would like to perhaps not remove but
可能想删除但
supplant make it make it easier for
取代使其更容易
programmers to work with immutable non
程序员与不可变的非
mutable persistent constant data
可变的持久常数数据
structures and have that be the
结构，并具有
notational sweet spot rather than
注释性的最佳点，而不是
currently which is everything is mutable
目前这一切都是可变的
and everything has a race condition in
一切都有种族条件
it I'll second that one I think closure
我将第二个我认为关闭
has found a really nice balance between
找到了一个非常好的平衡
mutable
易变的
immutable yeah they're that they're
永恒的，是的，他们是，他们是
definitely good ideas to be to be
绝对是个好主意
studied there mutability is the
研究那里可变性是
exception should have to pay for every
例外应该为每一件事付出代价
use of the assignment operator and the
使用赋值运算符和
price goes up with every version yeah
价格随每个版本而增加
hey revenue opportunity new business
嘿，收入机会，新业务
Manu oh yeah so jigsaw we know i'm sure
Manu哦，是的，所以拼图，我们知道我确定
you guys knew at the very beginning i
你们从一开始就知道
was going to be very difficult to pull
很难拉
off and been proven by how long has
并被证明有多长时间了
taken it was there have to be even
采取它必须有甚至
harder as you dug in were there things
挖东西时更难
that you're like how the hell did that
你就像是怎么了
even work i mean as you tried to dig in
甚至是工作，我的意思是您尝试挖掘
even with all the preparation were the
即使进行了所有准备工作
things that just totally surprised you
让你完全惊讶的事情
that we're in the product as you try to
您尝试使用我们的产品时
give me things inside the jdk yeah yeah
给我JDK里面的东西是的
some of the cross connections like those
一些像这样的交叉连接
those six methods that we're removing in
我们要删除的六种方法
nine so i actually have a bit of fun
九点，所以我实际上很有趣
here so John why did why did the pack
在这里，约翰为什么要为什么打包
200 API need event listeners because of
由于以下原因，需要200个API的事件监听器
progress bars I apologize seemed like a
我道歉的进度条看起来像一个
good idea at the time that's a it's a
当时的好主意是
legitimate reason but amongst the
正当理由，但其中
methods we removed for the event
我们为事件删除的方法
listener methods unpacked nadra oh sorry
侦听器方法解压缩后的nadra哦，抱歉
sorry they're gone yeah I me there there
对不起，他们走了，是的，我在那里
there were lots of surprising things on
上有很多令人惊讶的事情
the plus side you know there was
你知道那边的好处
fortunately a fair amount of informal
幸运的是，相当数量的非正式
discipline over the years you know even
你甚至知道多年来的纪律
going back to the very beginning to try
回到最开始尝试
to keep things clean to try not to have
保持东西干净，尽量不要
gratuitous dependencies I mean sure we
无缘无故的依赖，我是说确定
found stuff where you know some some
在你知道一些东西的地方找到了东西
code in the corporate implementation was
公司实施中的代码是
reaching into the guts of the XML parser
深入了解XML解析器
like oh really but I you know I remember
真的喜欢，但是我知道我记得
back in the day working on 11 with the
回到那天与11
first release I worked on and I happen
我开发的第一个版本发生了
to notice that you know a well-meaning
注意到你知道一个善意的人
engineer and the AWT team had put some
工程师和AWT团队投入了一些
get icon methods into java.lang system
将图标方法放入java.lang系统
which seems like a good idea i mean neo
这似乎是个好主意，我的意思是新
you might want methods in the system to
您可能希望系统中的方法
get icons for the running java program
获取正在运行的Java程序的图标
or whatever
管他呢
and I went and asked to meal in Lindhome
我去找林德美吃饭
about it and he said what because it was
关于它，他说什么，因为那是
just an obvious you know even though we
尽管我们知道
didn't have modules it was just an
没有模块，那只是一个
obvious violation of what informal
明显违反非正式
substance systems we had and so you know
我们拥有的物质系统，所以您知道
I'm grateful we had at least the
我很感激我们至少有
informal discipline over the years so
多年来的非正式纪律
that it wasn't so painful that only took
并没有那么痛苦，只花了
like five years to detangle the JDK more
像五年来更多地纠缠JDK
than that we started in 2008 it's 530
比我们在2008年开始的数字530
last question any chance to bring
最后一个问题带来的机会
features from alec project home park
Alec Project Home Park的功能
into the GDK or any plan to reduce the
进入GDK或任何旨在减少
amount of boat up on a plate I I believe
相信船上的船数量
there would be zero chance of features
功能的机会为零
specifically from project lombok coming
特别是来自 lombok 项目
into the JDK by Brian would you agree
你同意Brian进入JDK
with that somebody missed the keynote so
有人错过了主题演讲，所以
at the keynote on on Sunday we did talk
在周日的主题演讲中，我们确实做了讨论
about boilerplate reduction features
关于样板减少功能
they were not specifically a project
他们不是专门的项目
lombok but we we do care a lot about
lombok ，但我们确实很在乎
boilerplate and we do have you know a
样板，我们确实知道您
number of features on deck for
甲板上的功能数量
eliminating every day boilerplate we
消除每天的样板
showed local variable type inference we
显示了局部变量类型推断
showed the ability of the compiler to
显示了编译器的能力
generate default constructor equals hash
生成默认的构造函数等于哈希
code to string you know type operations
字符串，您知道类型操作的代码
so so yes but you know exactly what
所以是的，但是你确切知道什么
those features are when they are what
这些功能是什么时候
version they come in to be determined
他们来确定的版本
and maybe they make it easier to program
也许它们使编程变得更容易
without mutability need okay one last
没有可变性就可以了
item this just in from Sean Mullan are
刚刚来自肖恩·穆兰的商品
our security lead the Microsoft RSS
我们的安全负责人Microsoft RSS
RSASS a issue is known for other people
RSASS问题为其他人所熟知
have reported that we will look into it
报告说我们会调查一下
after John Tolin all right with that
在约翰·托林之后
thank you very much thanks
非常感谢你，谢谢